[AWAKEN]
[Episode 7]
We sent her to deliver invitations
for the charity sale.
Is there a problem with that?
Just a routine inquiry. Don't be nervous.
Take a picture.
[Shanghai Ciji Foundation
Membership Application Form]
This is Shen Kexi's file
at the Ciji Foundation.
Volunteer Shen
has been here for almost a year.
She mainly works the night shift,
and she only interacts with people
from Ciji Foundation
and those receiving relief.
Her social life is very simple and clean.
No. 76 must have made a mistake.
Where does she usually live?
We have our own dormitory.
Everyone lives together.
Okay, thank you.
Did you take the picture?
I did.
This is your first time here, right?
Are you thinking about that woman?
Will she die?
You said she's a Communist.
She denied it.
Her feet were nailed to the ground,
and she still denied it.
Communists are pretty much all like that.
What do you think...
faith is?
Probably something worth living for.
Do you have it?
You definitely don't.
I do.
Cigarettes, alcohol,
and beautiful women.
Are all the people from No. 76
like you,
selfish, hedonistic,
and heartless?
Aren't you also working for No. 76?
I'm not like you.
How are you different?
You are too cruel.
You're not human.
Sometimes what you see
isn't necessarily the truth.
Do you still need the pictures?
They don't prove she's a Communist.
Handing them in would be useless.
Su Causeway has been arrested.
[Yan'an]
[He Yufeng, Chief of the CCP
Enemy Area Work Department]
Requesting rescue.
Diana.
Reply.
Awaken Leifeng Pagoda.
Taking photos?
I'm Xin Xiang.
[Xin Xiang, Photo Studio Apprentice]
I'm the new shop assistant.
Jinbao.
Jinbao!
What?
Who's the guy at the door?
You spend all your time
with that female official.
If we don't find someone
to watch the shop,
it'll close sooner or later.
Where did you find him?
Let him learn photography from you.
He's cheap and obedient.
Aren't you coming in?
This is your master.
Introduce yourself first.
Hello, I'm Xin Xiang.
I worked at Sanchuan Photo Studio before,
but my master's skills were poor,
so I jumped ship.
I'm not stupid.
In a place like that, even if I worked
until I was 99,
I'd never make it.
As if you could live to 99.
Right.
Whatever you say is right, Master.
I'm not your master.
I'm your boss.
Nonsense.
I'm the boss.
There's an empty room for you
by the stairs.
Go upstairs and get your things together.
Okay, Boss.
Don't smile so creepily.
Boss, come.
Sit, sit.
Can you lend me some money?
For what?
To save someone.
Who?
My cousin.
Your cousin?
How come you suddenly
have a cousin in Shanghai?
It's the lady who came here
when we just opened.
You said she looked like a star.
She's your cousin?
Who are you trying to fool?
She looked familiar
the last time I saw her.
We ran into each other again later
and recognized each other.
She was caught by No. 76.
They said she's a Communist.
So is she?
They pierced her feet,
and she still denied it.
What do you think?
So cruel?
How much do you want?
5,000.
Also,
you know a lot of people.
Can you ask around
to see who can get her out?
Cang Guanglian from last time
definitely won't do.
He's a fraud.
How about 10,000?
5,000 is indeed a bit too little.
Go to sleep.
You can have anything in your dreams.
A life is at stake.
You can't just leave her to die.
My cousin is definitely a good person.
Let me tell you,
I only care about money now, not people.
I just think
you're the best person in the world,
so I came to you for help.
Flattery won't work.
You dare to get involved with anything
related to the Communist Party?
You'll get yourself killed one day.
She's your cousin,
not your father.
Anyway, I have to save her.
If you get yourself killed,
find a place to bury yourself.
I won't collect your corpse.
Didn't you help me
when I was in trouble last time?
You have a mind of your own.
I can't stop you.
Think it through yourself.
Since No. 76 says she's a Communist,
it's impossible to get her out
just by spending some money.
Everyone went to the ball!
And I had to spend
the whole night here because of you!
Kill me.
What did you say?
Kill you?
I won't.
I'll give you one more chance.
Will you talk?
If you're happy,
why don't you have a drink with me?
Alright, stop talking.
Dance with me.
Director Li.
Okay.
Got a cigarette?
You should be more of a gentleman.
Nice ring.
Where did you buy it?
I had a silversmith make it.
You can't buy such a good ring.
Which silversmith?
Hello, Leifeng Pagoda.
The Organization has decided
to rescue Shen Kexi at all costs.
How?
Aren't we going to dance?
Her feet are nailed to the ground.
How can I be in the mood to dance?
Find a way to send her to the hospital.
Inspector Su.
I... I want to ask you for a dance.
Do you know how to dance?
You can teach me.
There are plenty of dancers
at Great Shanghai Ballroom.
Find them if you want to learn.
Inspector Su,
I want to show you something.
I've been to the Ciji Foundation.
She really is a volunteer.
She's been working there for a while.
It was just her job
to deliver things to Ouyang.
This is the evidence.
Didn't you want to ask me for a dance?
What's your relationship with her?
No lying.
We knew each other when we were kids.
She took
some photos at my shop before.
Are you very close?
No.
Then why?
Playing the hero saving the beauty?
I'm not a hero.
I'm someone who was wronged by them.
So is she.
I said,
no lying.
I'm not lying.
She's a good person, not a Communist.
That's a dangerous thing to say.
I haven't told anyone else.
Then why did you come to me?
I think you're different from the others.
You're wrong.
I'm just like Li Moqun.
We both work for the Japanese.
Just like you said,
we are traitors.
But she really is a good person.
I have proof.
At No. 76,
proof is the most useless thing.
Don't mention it again.
So you're just going to watch
an innocent person
be framed?
Watch your mouth.
If you don't want it anymore,
just say the word.
Inspector Su,
if this is the kind of person you are,
I don't want to work for you anymore.
I'm afraid karma will catch up with me.
Stop right there.
Do you know why I'm not helping you?
Because your dancing
is terrible.
Give me back the photo.
I'll burn it for you.
It's dangerous to keep it.
I could only hold my camera like an idiot,
standing there watching her suffer,
unable to do anything.
I told you a long time ago,
in these times,
a camera can't save lives.
At that moment, I wished
I had a gun in my hand.
I would point it at
that bastard Cang Guanglian's head
and blow his brains out.
You're finally getting it.
I'm telling you,
learn from me,
and that day will come sooner or later.
Blow his brains out.
But right now,
I'm useless.
I can't save her.
It's okay.
I'll help you.
You?
I am Battalion Commander Du.
Give me a gun,
and those idiots
won't be enough for me to deal with.
Brother.
From today on,
you are my brother.
Let's charge in together
and put that bastard Cang down, okay?
Blow his brains out!
Be honest with me.
Is she really a Communist?
Boss.
No. 76 is too greedy.
They extorted 300,000 silver dollars
at once.
That's 300,000 silver dollars.
I've never seen so much money in my life.
Look.
[Flour King Slams No. 76
for Kidnapping and Extortion]
Where is Chen Kailai?
He drank too much last night.
He's probably still sleeping.
Chen Kailai!
Get up!
Don't bother me.
I'm not going to No. 76.
Look at this.
What?
It's not the first time
No. 76 has done this.
But this time, it's become a big deal.
People outside are protesting
about your cousin.
No more unjust persecution!
No more kidnapping and brutality!
Release the innocent volunteer!
No more unjust persecution!
Idiot!
If you had gotten something
out of her earlier,
would things have turned out like this?
Director, I specifically checked
with the Ciji Foundation.
She is indeed a volunteer there.
And it's true
that she was delivering invitations
to past donors.
Well...
Did we...
catch the wrong person?
Did we?
No.
We definitely didn't.
This woman must be a Communist.
Why?
Wh-
She's too stubborn.
No more unjust persecution!
No more kidnapping and brutality!
You need to be more ruthless.
I'm afraid she can't take it.
I can barely take it myself!
Before dark,
no matter what it takes,
you must make her talk!
Understood.
Where is Captain Cang?
He was called away by Director Li.
Pan-fried buns.
From Dahuchun.
Thank you, Section Chief Zhao.
She still won't talk?
No, she still won't talk.
Is she awake?
I've never seen anyone so stubborn!
Why so angry?
Because of her.
I haven't eaten all night.
If she still won't talk,
it means your methods aren't working.
To deal with women,
you have to use
both the carrot and the stick.
I just finished appeasing Director Li.
Now I have to coax her?
Am I that pathetic?
I'm worried
you've been hitting her too hard.
Before you can make her talk,
what if she dies?
If she's sent to the hospital
and they can't save her,
who's going to take the fall?
Why don't you do it?
Help me out.
I haven't slept all night.
I can't do interrogations.
The Logistics Section only delivers food.
You just know how to mess with me.
You are a hot potato.
Brother,
the Director's throwing another fit.
They're gathering at our door.
How could he not be angry?
You are really tough.
She passed out again.
Get some water. Get some water.
Wake her up!
It's raining so hard outside.
Did you take a car here?
I took the tram.
When the driver comes back later,
I'll have him take you home.
Please don't bother.
On the way here just now,
I passed by Jing'an Temple
and saw several tailor shops.
I'd like to look around.
Miss Ouyang,
do you have any tailors to recommend?
It's hard for me to recommend it.
Miss Shen, you're so beautiful.
You'll look good in anything.
From the Ciji Foundation
to Ouyang's house,
you don't pass by Jing'an Temple at all.
They are in two different directions.
So I think
she was testing the waters,
or rather,
it's a secret signal.
In that case, she really is fishy.
Release the innocent volunteer!
No more unjust persecution!
No more kidnapping and brutality!
Release the innocent volunteer!
But if you tell the people down there
that this woman is definitely a Communist
because she passed by Jing'an Temple,
will they believe it?
That's why
we need to secure her confession.
Let me give you an idea, Director Li.
I'm all ears.
Since she is Ouyang's accomplice,
we can bring Ouyang here to identify her.
Then she won't be able to deny it.
Ouyang is detained
by the Plum Blossom Agency.
We can't get her out.
You can discuss it with General Kagesa.
There's no room for discussion.
I might as well figure out a way myself.
I have to say,
Captain Cang is brave
but lacks wisdom.
Even if he beat her to death,
he might not get anything out of her.
Well...
Come in.
Director.
That woman couldn't take it,
and she passed out.
Go wake her up.
We tried everything,
but... but she didn't respond.
Send her to the hospital then.
What are you waiting for?
Listen to Inspector Su
and send her to Renji Hospital
immediately.
Yes.
The tea is good.
We should go visit the wounded too.
Didn't you say you weren't coming?
You published the photo, right?
Thank you.
It has nothing to do with me.
From now on,
I'm at your service anytime.
Bring your camera
and let's go.
Where are you going?
This way! This way!
Be careful!
Close the door.
Come on.
Give me a hand. Come on.
Come on. Slowly.
One, two, three!
Pull it out. Open the door.
She can still be saved.
Clean the wounds first.
Get him out of here.
Yes.
Excuse me, please go somewhere else.
You two,
guard that entrance.
Yes.
Let's go have a smoke.
Keep a close watch.
Yes.
Why is this woman here?
Seems like she's visiting the wounded
from the racecourse shooting.
She never misses a chance
to get attention.
Get ready for action.
Got a light?
Here, have a smoke.
No smoking here.
Go outside if you want to smoke.
Let's go smoke. Come on.
Take good care of him.
Thank you.
Take good care of yourself.
Thank you, officer.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
I just came to visit you.
Thank you.
[Closed]
[Under Maintenance]
Nurse!
Are they trying to save a woman inside?
Yes.
In her twenties, with injured feet?
Is she still alive?
If you keep stopping me
from getting medicine,
she probably won't survive.
Go. Go quickly.
Doctor, come take a look!
Doctor.
What's wrong?
Take a look quickly, doctor.
Doctor.
Come and look.
Look.
Family members, wait outside.
Drive to the back door of the hospital.
Hurry up!
Don't be nervous. Relax.
You're about to give birth.
-What happened?
-Where is she?
Where is she?
What's going on?
Where did she go?
I don't...
I don't know.
Where is she?
She was... She was taken away!
Let's go!
What happened?
Who opened the door?
Speak!
What's wrong? She's about to give birth?
Go tell her family
that the pregnant woman
is about to give birth,
and that she needs
to go to the delivery room.
Family members?
She is about to give birth.
She needs to go to the delivery room.
She's about to give birth?
Give me the keys.
Nobody move.
Go over there.
What happened?
She went missing.
Before our men could act.
Inspector Su!
Your car was hijacked.
Where did it happen?
At the back door.
Captain, it's here.
When we chased them out,
it looked like Inspector Su's car
drove away from here.
Inspector Su?
I was just looking for you.
Where is my car?
It seems the Communists took her away
using your car
right from here.
Are you suspecting me, Captain Cang?
I wouldn't dare.
My driver was taken hostage,
and the Communist was taken away.
All of this
is because of your incompetence.
You'd better think about
how to explain this to Director Li
when you get back.
Do you really suspect her?
Director Li will have the final say.
What did you see just now?
I saw them hijack your car.
How many people were there?
Three or four.
This doesn't have anything to do with you,
does it?
How is that possible?
You called me here.
You can go back first.
[Renji Hospital]
Besides us,
who else would have saved Su Causeway?
They used your car.
I'm afraid they're coming for you.
No matter who they were,
I hope she's okay.
I'm worried about her feet.
Will she ever be able to walk again?
Sir, hurry up.
Brother,
we brought her back.
Did it go smoothly?
Minister Zhou.
I suspect Inspector Su Men
of colluding with the Communists.
I will definitely find evidence.
Yes.
Go.
Find evidence immediately.
You must find that car.
It's your duty
to see this through.
Understood.
Where is Shen Kexi?
Where?
It really was you guys who saved her?
Ow, ow, ow!
Let him go.
It's almost done. Get the medicine ready.
Where did you get this medicine?
Penicillin is more expensive than gold.
Gold isn't as useful as this.
Why did you save her?
I do whatever the Battalion Commander
tells me to do.
Go, cut her sleeve off.
Slowly, slowly.
You can go out first.
Cover her up a bit.
Help me.
Hold it down.
Her life is saved.
What exactly do you do?
You even know how to perform surgery?
Do you know what she does?
She's my cousin.
What's her identity?
A volunteer for the Ciji Foundation.
Is that all you know?
Let me tell you.
She is our comrade.
Comrade?
You're both Communists?
Don't we look like it?
I just didn't expect
that a Nationalist battalion commander
like you
would also be a Communist.
What's wrong with being a Communist?
I know better than you
how Nanjing was lost by Tang Shengzhi.
So you joined the Communist Party?
Then what makes you think
my cousin is also a Communist?
No one could endure such torture.
She's out of danger now.
What's wrong?
Thank you, Battalion Commander Du.
No, Brother Du.
Call me Master.
There's another thing I don't understand.
What is it?
How did you know
she would be at that hospital?
Do you have people in No. 76 too?
Do you think it was a coincidence?
Impossible.
There are so many people in Shanghai
who want to harm me,
but the only one who could pull it off
is him.
No matter who it is,
they're not worth another drink.